# **CHYNA DAVIS**

## Tucson, Arizona | Web Developer & Linguist

phone (CELL): (520) 269-1481 | email: chyna.davis11@gmail.com

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/chyna-davis | **Web Portfolio:** https://chynadavis.netlify.app/

\_\_\_\_\_

Web Developer specializing in Front-End technologies; has an extensive background in Linguistics and foreign languages, as well as ESL teaching experience overseas. Graduated from the University of Arizona with a Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics with a minor in Japanese Language. Studies focused on Linguistics, Psychology, East Asian Studies, Gender Studies, Linguistic Anthropology, History, Religion, and Political Geography. Has studied foreign languages in intensive and immersive environments, and possesses excellent command of Japanese and Mandarin Chinese. Also proficient with various computer technologies and languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Microsoft Office, and Adobe Creative Cloud. Can adapt to and work in repetitive and fast-paced environments, is detail-oriented, and learns new skills quickly.

SKILLS -----

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Full-Stack Web Development (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, REST APIs, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, React.js, testing/debugging, Git version control, etc.)
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
- Adobe Creative Cloud (Illustrator, Photoshop, Dreamweaver)

#### **OTHER SKILLS:**

- languages: English (native speaker), Japanese (advanced), and Mandarin Chinese (intermediate)
- time management, multitasking, oral and written communication, adaptability, team collaboration, problem-solving, organization, attention to detail

## WORK EXPERIENCE -----

Tucson Foundations - Data Entry Clerk (Part-Time) (Nov 2020 - present)

- enter and retrieve data using various technologies such as Microsoft Excel
- make scans and review documents for errors

Little Planet U-unique English Classroom (Taichung, Taiwan) - ESL Teacher (Part-Time) (Mar 2018 - Jun 2019)

- taught English reading and writing skills to middle and high school students
- gave oral/written tests and graded class and homework assignments
- tutored 1-on-1 for university essays, standardized tests, homework help, etc.

### EDUCATION ------

University of Arizona Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp - Certificate of Completion (240 hours) (Feb - Jul 2020)

24-week intensive Full-Stack web development program; graduated with an A+

Tunghai University Chinese Language Center - Certificate of Completion (720 hours) (Mar 2018 - Jun 2019)

• three semesters of immersive study in Taichung, Taiwan with focus on mastering speaking, listening, reading, and writing skills; earned grade A

University of Arizona - Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics (Aug 2013 - May 2017)

- minor in Japanese language
- graduated Magna Cum Laude with 3.85 GPA